MUHAMMAD SHAMEER M

UI DEVELOPER

ABOUT ME

I am a versatile UI Developer with 4+ years of experience in design, development and management of complex web applications. I am skilled in **UX / UI Designing, HTML, CSS, JavaScript** and **React JS**. I am an engineering professional with a Master's degree focused in Computer Application from University of Calicut.

EXPERIENCE

UI DEVELOPER

Neointeraction Designs, Bengaluru, India / May 2016 - Present

- Accepted full-time position as UI developer.
- Developed prototypes and high-quality mockups for clients to ensure quality control and client satisfaction before project development phase.
- Used Component Driven Development (CDD) approach to develop and maintain complex web components using React and StoryBook.
- Developed fully functional responsive applications based on Business Requirements using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript while taking advantage of the frameworks like ReactJS.
- Performed cross-browser testing, debugging, website maintenance and enhancements.
- Worked onsite as UI Engineer with a development team for a reputed company in Indonesia.

WEB DEVELOPER

Freelance, Palakkad, India / October 2015 – May 2016

- Designed and developed fully functional responsive websites for clients using HTML, CSS, JQuery and PHP.
- Performed cross-browser testing and debugging.
- Performed website maintenance and enhancements.

Portfolio URL: https://mshameer237.github.io/

PERSONAL

Single, Male, 18 June 1991

- mshameer237@gmail.com
- 7012860484, 8884771092
- #101, first floor, 33rd Main, Dollars Scheme Colony, 1st Stage, BTM Layout, Bengaluru, Karnataka 560068,
- in linkedin.com/in/shameerm

SKILLS

Coding: HTML5, CSS3,

JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap,

SASS, React, Material-UI,

StoryBook , Git , React-Native,

Expo, TypeScript

Design: Adobe XD, Sketch,

InVision, Axure.

EDUCATION

MCA

Calicut University, 2012 - 2015

BSc. Computer Science

Bharathiar University 2009 - 2012